Guide to the Foster Hall Collection, 1800-1952 CAM.FHC.2011.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Stephen Foster, 1837-1900; I.
  - Post-Mortem Royalty Statements & Correspondence, 1864-1900; 5.
    - Letter from William A. Pond & Co. to Morrison Foster, July 8, 1879; D236
      Agreeing to his proposition from June to pay Marion & Jane a three cents per copy royalty, and $100 advance. Would like the heirs to recognize the reentry. Emphasizes that it's legal to re-copyright under the publisher's name provided heirs assent to it. Morrison's response on back indicates that it is Pond's responsibility (and expense) to re-enter copyrights. Wants the $1.00 it cost him to reenter "Oh, Boys."
    - Letter from Morrison Foster to William A. Pond & Co., May 31, 1879; D237
      This letter is a copy. Granting permission to publish songs for 3 and 4 cent royalty. Lists songs. Requesting $20.00 advance against royalties. Copyrights must be taken out in Jane and Marion's names. Asking if anything was done about those songs originally copyrighted in 1849 and 1850, as well as "Farewell Old Cottage." Also wants a copy of previous royalties.
    - Library of Congress Directions for Securing Copyrights, 1888; D238
    - Library of Congress Directions Securing Copyrights, 1874; D239
    - Letter from Library of Congress to Morrison Foster, May 14, 1889; D240
      Regarding copyright dates he queried.
    - Cover letter for agreement from Attorney George Murray to Morrison Foster, July 3, 1889; D241a
      Regarding Morrison Foster's proposed contract with S.T. Gordon. Morrison's response in his hand on bottom; authorized $10 advance. Includes two copies of the agreement.
    - Agreement from Attorney George Murray to Morrison Foster (copy for Gordon & Son), July 3, 1889; 241b
    - Agreement from Attorney George Murray to Morrison Foster (Morrison Foster's copy), July 3, 1889; 241c
    - Letter from S.T. Gordon & Son to Morrison Foster, April 15, 1889; D242
      Request to renew copyrights for Foster's compositions held by Gordon.
    - Letter from S.T. Gordon & Son to Morrison Foster, April 22, 1889; D243
      Denying Morrison's request to have Gordon list all of their Foster titles and when the copyrights run out as it's too much work.
    - Letter from Attorney George F. Murray to Morrison Foster, July 9, 1889; D244
      Regarding the contract Morrison is attempting to negotiate with S.T. Gordon.
    - Letter from S.T. Gordon to Morrison Foster, July 9, 1889; D245
      Declining Morrison's request for a $10 advance to renew "Why Have My Loved Ones Gone."
    - Letter from Library of Congress to Morrison Foster, June 28, 1889; D246
      Info on renewing copyright. Note in Morrison's hand that there is no certificate of copyright and that S.T. Gordon will take care of taking it out.
    - Letter from Morrison Foster to Library of Congress, June 26, 1889; D247
      Inquiring about submitting "Why Have My Loved Ones Gone" for re-copyright. Item is a copy.
    - Letter from S.T. Gordon to Morrison Foster, June 22, 1889; D248
      Request to resubmit "Why Have My Loved Ones Gone?" for copyright.
    - Letter from S.T. Gordon & Son to Morrison Foster, May 9, 1889; D249
      Requesting a response to his request for renewing Why Have My Loved Ones Gone.
    - Letter from S.T. Gordon & Son to Morrison Foster, May 14, 1889; D250
    - From Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, April 28, 1879; D251
      Alerting him that they have all the business plates & rights from Firth Pond and a convoluted tale of their trying to renew copyright for "Old Folks at Home."
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Mrs. Stephen Foster (Jane Wiley), March 29, 1879; D252
      Trying to contact her.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Mrs. Stephen Foster (Jane D. Wiley), April 22, 1879; D253
      Wants to renew "Old Folks at Home" copyright, offering her either a royalty or $100 flat.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, May 13, 1879; D254
      Responding to Morrison's modifications to contract, requesting only two royalty periods rather than four, and indicating that it is not in their practice to pay for arrangements
    - Letter/agreement from Morrison Foster to Oliver Ditson, May 10, 1879; D255
      Item is a copy. Draft agreement requesting checks be made payable to Jane's married name, requesting removal of Christy's name from "Old Folks at Home," granting permission to renew "Old Folks at Home."
    - Letter from Morrison Foster to Oliver Ditson & Co., May 5, 1879; D256
      Item is a copy; describing how Christy came to be listed as author of OFAH, offering to renew copyright if they pay Jane $100 plus 3 cent royalty.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, May 19, 1879; D257
      Agreeing to his terms.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, August 2, 1880; D258
      Enclosing payment of $132.00.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, May 7, 1879; D259
      Terms accepted; clipping of new copyright notice enclosed.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, March 18, 1881; D260
      Print run of "Old Folks at Home," royalty periods.
    - January 1881 cover letter & royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., March 12, 1881; D261
      $72.60 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand of how he dispersed funds.
    - Cover letter for July 1882 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., August 2, 1882; D262a
      $94.11 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand of how he dispersed funds. Includes request from the Yale College Songs editor to include "Old Folks at Home" in their collection.
    - July 1882 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., August 2, 1882; D262b
    - January 1882 royalty statement, January 1, 1882; D263
      $110.28 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand of how he dispersed funds.
    - July 1882 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1882; D264
      $125.88 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand of how he dispersed funds.
    - Postcard from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, February 4, 1883; D265
      Reassuring him that the Yale Songbook will correct "Old Folks at Home" in next edition.
    - July 1883 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1883; D266
      $71.45 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how the funds were dispersed.
    - January 1883 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1883; D267
      $151.88 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how the funds were dispersed.
    - January 1884 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1884; D268
      $37.15 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how the funds were dispersed.
    - Letter from Jane (Foster) Wiley to Morrison Foster, August 24, 1884; D269
      Acknowledging that she received the July royalties.
    - Cover letter for July 1884 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., August 15, 1884; D270a
      $80.63 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1884 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., August 15, 1884; D270b
    - Cover letter for January 1885 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 3, 1885; D271a
      $85.60 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1885 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1885; D271b
      $85.89 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed the funds.
    - January 1886 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 23, 1886; D272
      $69.90 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1886 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1886; D273
      $100.08 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed the funds.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, August 31, 1886; D274
      Asking him to forward sheet music to Jane.
    - January 1887 royalties and cover letter from Oliver Ditson & Co., February 3, 1887; D275
      $30.96 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1887 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1887; D276
      $131.63 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed funds.
    - January 1888 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1888; D277
      $61.11 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed funds.
    - July 1887 royalty statement from William A. Pond & Co., July 1, 1887; D278
      $77.25 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed funds.
    - July 1888 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1888; D279
      $161.10 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed funds.
    - January 1889 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1889; D280
      $61.41 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed funds.
    - July 1889 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1889; D281
      $94.56 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand indicating how he dispersed funds.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, February 13, 1889; D282
      Regarding check from Ticknor & Co. for "Massa's in de Cold Ground." On back of letter is Morrison's notes about how he distributed the money.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, December 17, 1889; D283
      Cover letter and signed agreement to pursue legal action against Echo Music for copyright infringement.
    - Letter from Oliver Ditson & Co. to Morrison Foster, December 10, 1889; D284
      Regarding pursuing legal action against Echo Music Co. for copyright violation.
    - January 1890 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1890; D285
      $77.61 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - January 1891 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1891; D286
      $81.37 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1891 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1891; D287
      $84.30 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1890 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1890; D288
      $181.57 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - Letter from Jane (Foster) Wiley to Morrison Foster, August 10, 1890; D289
      Acknowledgement that she received his royalty check.
    - January 1892 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1892; D290
      $88.97 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1882 royalty statement from William A. Pond & Co., August 10, 1882; D291
      $19.65 in royalties.
    - January 1887 royalty statement from William A. Pond & Co., January 1, 1887; D292
      $15.75 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1884 royalty statement from William A. Pond & Co., July 1, 1884; D293
      $23.25 in royalties.
    - January 1884 royalty statement from William A. Pond & Co., January 1, 1884; D294
      $27.60 in royalties.
    - January 1884 royalty statement from William A. Pond & Co., January 1, 1884; D295
      On notepaper. Not a duplicate of D294. A continuation perhaps?
    - July 1883 royalty statement from William A. Pond & Co., July 1, 1883; D296
      $36.75 in royalties. On notepaper.
    - January 1886 royalties from William A. Pond & Co., January 1, 1886; D297
      $46.50 in royalties.
    - July 1892 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1892; D298
      $133.00 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - January 1893 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1893; D299
      $66.91 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1893 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson Company, July 1, 1893; D300
      $85.64 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - January 1894 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., January 1, 1894; D301
      $21.76 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1894 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Co., July 1, 1894; D302
      $15.25 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - January 1895 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson Company, January 1, 1895; D303
      $10.59 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - July 1895 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson Company, July 1, 1895; D304
      .90 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - January 1896 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson Company, January 1, 1896; D305
      .90 in royalty. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds. Also a note that Ditson has no permit to publish the two songs ("Gentle Annie" and "Nelly Bly").
    - January 1897 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson & Company, January 1, 1897; D306
      .90 in royalty. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - January 1898 royalty statement from Oliver Ditson Company, January 1, 1898; D307
      $7.95 in royalties. Note in Morrison's hand regarding how he dispersed the funds.
    - Library of Congress Copyright Certificate for "Old Folks Quadrilles", February 28, 1881; D308
      Copyright renewal for "Old Folks Quadrilles."
    - Library of Congress copyright certificate for "Comrades Fill No Glass for Me", July 11, 1883; D309
      Copyright renewal.
    - Library of Congress copyright certificate for "Village Maiden", July 11, 1883; D310
    - Library of Congress copyright certificate for "Oh Boys Carry Me 'Long", June 21, 1879; D311
      Copyright renewal
    - Library of Congress copyright certificate for "Little Ella", November 14, 1881; D312
    - Letter from Library of Congress to Morrison Foster, June 23, 1883; D313
      Quoting rates for copyright renewal certificates.
    - Letter from Library of Congress to Morrison Foster, April 19, 1883; D314
      Sending him info on "Village Maiden" and "Comrades Fill No Glass for Me."
    - Letter from Library of Congress to Morrison Foster, December 10, 1881; D315
      Sending him the report of the party making copyright searches.
    - Copyright submission of "The White House Chair", September 3, 1885; D316
      Remitted to Library of Congress on Sept 2, 1885. Copyright #18766 issued Sept. 4, 1885
    - Library of Congress Directions for Securing Copyrights, 1883; D317
      Note that this has since been amended.
    - Library of Congress Directions for Securing Copyrights, 1888; D318
      Note that it was received in June 1889.
    - List of songs and copyright dates for pieces that Foster only wrote the music for, undated; D319
    - Copyright request for "Why Have My Loved Ones Gone", June 26, 1889; D320
      Submitted by Morrison Foster to Library of Congress with $.50 fee to renew copyright in Jane and Marion's names.
    - 1831 copyright law assigning rights to widows and children, D321
      Handwritten transcription of the act of February 3, 1831.
    - List of Foster songs with copyright dates and publishers (when known), titled 1879 at the top, D322a
      Four separate lists, three in pencil one in pen, most likely in Morrison Foster's hand.
    - List of Foster songs with copyright dates and publishers (when known), titled 1851 at the top, unknown; D322b
    - List of Foster songs published by William A. Pond, undated; D322c
    - List of Foster songs from 1853 and 1854, undated; D322d
    - Letter from Morrison Foster to J.O. Parmlee, Esq., Dec. 17, 1896 (Folder D323)
- Foster Family, 1800-1952; II.
  This series includes possessions, correspondence, photographs, manuscripts, and business records of Stephen Foster's immediate family, including his parents, siblings, daughter and niece. Much of the correspondence and records pre-date Foster's birth and help to provide a vivid picture of Pittsburgh during the first half of the 19th century.
  - Foster Family Photos, 1800-1900; 1.
    This subseries contains original photographs of members of Stephen Foster's immediate family.
    - Daguerreotype of William B. Foster, Sr. and Eliza Clayland Tomlinson Foster, ca. 1840s; A365; Copies are 14203
    - Photograph of Marion Foster as a young girl, undated; 00094
    - Henrietta Foster Thornton with two sons, undated; 15092
    - Photo of Henrietta Crosman in As You Like It, undated; C472
  - Foster Family Books, 1800-1900; 2.
    This subseries includes published books owned by Foster family members.
    - Jane Foster's Prayer Book, 1854; A222
    - Pennsylvania Railroad Men's News, Vol. 9, No. 8, August 1897; C733
      Includes an article on the History of the PA Railroad company, written by William B. Foster, Jr.
    - Excursion Trip of the Directors & Officers of the Pennsylvania R.R. Co., October 3, 1859; C735
      Includes a lock of William B. Foster, Jr.'s, hair.
    - Latest Illustrated Reference Family Bible (NY: Bartlett & Jenkins), 1873; D329
      Morneweck Family bible, presented to Ephraim and Harriet Hanson Morneweck, married December 25, 1877 by Alfred and Mary Lamb Hanson. Includes some family photos pasted in at back.
    - The Holy Bible containing the Old and New Testaments together with the Apocrypha (New York: E. Duyckinck, Smith and Forman), 1812; D330
      Foster Family Bible, from William Foster, Sr., includes bio of William Foster written by Percy Smith, lots of handwritten genealogical information and Eliza Foster's obituaries.
  - Foster Family Manuscripts, 1800-1900; 3.
    This subseries contains manuscripts created by Stephen Foster's immediate family, including correspondence, original writings, and scrapbooks.
    - Correspondence, 1800-1950
      This section includes correspondence written by Stephen Foster's immediate family, in their hands and typed transcripts of some of the original correspondence written by Stephen Foster that is contained in the Stephen Foster series. Of particular note is the correspondence by Marion Foster Welsh, Stephen Foster's daughter, discussing her memories of her father and the rift that sprung up between her and other family members after his death.
      - From Eliza C. Foster to Daughter Henrietta, March 5, 1841; A303; Typed carbon copy available at C518.
      - From Eliza C. Foster to Daughter Henrietta, April 9, 1842; A304; Typed carbon copy available at C511
      - From Eliza C. Foster to Daughter Henrietta, July 20, 1842; A305; Typed transcript of letter at C503
      - From Eliza C. Foster to Son William B. Foster, Jr., May 14, 1832; A306
      - From Eliza C. Foster to William B. Foster, Jr., July 9, 1833; A307; typed transcript at C845
      - From William B. Foster to Daughter Henrietta, April 9, 1842; A313; typed carbon copy available at C512.
      - From William B. Foster to daughter Henrietta, October 29, 1842; A314
      - From William B. Foster to Son William Jr., September 3, 1841; A315; Photostat copy exists at C845
      - From Henry Baldwin Foster to Sister Henrietta, January 1, 1869; A316
      - From William Foster (Morrison's son), July 28, 1908; A317
      - From Jessie W. Rose to Dr. E.F. Strickland, June 23, 1903; A318
      - From Jessie W. Rose to Dr. E.F. Strickland, April 24, 1904; A320
      - From Jessie W. Rose to Mayor Cornelius Scully, November 14, 1939; A321
      - From Jane Foster to Morrison Foster, September 30, 1861; C578
      - From Jane Foster to Morrison Foster, October 5, 1861; C579
      - From Jane Foster to Morrison Foster, June 30, 1862; C580
      - From Jessie Rose Welch certifying authenticity of Stephen Foster manuscript book, June 1931; A319
      - From Henrietta Foster to William B. Foster, Jr., April 30, 1836; D331; typed transcript at C845
      - From Eliza Foster to Charlotte Foster, November 2, 1821; C393
        Encouraging Charlotte to be open in her letters and to save them; family returned from Greensburg; "your father has been drawing a few tunes on the violin for your little brother & sister to dance"; general info on neighbors, friends.
      - From Charlotte Foster to William B. Foster, Jr., March 17, 1828; C394
        To William in Kiskiminitis, mentions Stephen is "not quite well, he is still very weak"; earthquake; Caroline Grace & her piano; gossip.
      - From Charlotte Foster to Eliza C. Foster, October 27, 1828; C395
        Louisville; difficult for her to leave; Ann Eliza's upcoming wedding; social goings on; mention of Rowans; not serious about any of her beaus "I am too hard to please."
      - From Charlotte Foster to Eliza Foster, October 12, 1828; C396a
        Louisville; spent 3 weeks with Rowans at Federal Hill; justifying why she is still in KY despite their wishes; romantic goings on; "I believe I am to be an old maid"; A. Hill Rowan's proposal.
      - From Sarah Foster to Charlotte Foster, undated; C396b
        Must speak to Charlotte immediately about an unpleasant subject, show this note to no one.
      - From Eliza Foster to Charlotte Foster, October 4, 1828; C397
        Pittsburg; Father excited about election; Ann Eliza's new beau; Come home before your value is lessened.
      - From Rowan? to Charlotte Foster, October 3, 1828; C398
        Brief note to accompany letters the writer is carrying from Charlotte's parents.
      - From Charlotte Foster to William B. Foster, September 1828; C399
        Federal Hill; Judge Rowan claims her as a relation; responding to William's plea that she come home; descriptions of Rowans; "how is dear little Stephen I am uneasy about him?"
      - From William B. Foster to Charlotte Foster, September 7, 1828; C400
        Once again expresses fear for her health and urges her to return, commends the Kentucky election turn out, mentions local election, "Stephen was very unwell."
      - From Charlotte Foster to William B. Foster, Jr., August 13, 1828; C401
        From Louisville to William at Kiskiminitas, pleasure at hearing that he bought a new piano; Governor elections; social goings on.
      - From Charlotte Foster to Eliza Foster, August 12, 1828; C402
        From Louisville; just returned from country, pleasure at hearing about the piano, description of "Kentucky farmer's life," intention of going to Bardstown, KY, governor election; social goings on.
      - From Sally to Charlotte Foster, July 14, 1828; C403
        To Cincinnati; tales of Sally's life.
      - From Eliza Foster to Charlotte Foster, July 5, 1828; C404
        Pittsburgh to Louisville; concerned that it's been so long since she's written; Brother William's raise; election; if you need money, borrow it from the Barclay's; mend your clothes.
      - From Charlotte to William B. Foster, July 3, 1828; C405
        From Louisville; reassuring him that she is well; concerned about Eliza; desire for a piano at home; dislike of attending Catholic services; will go to Cincinnati soon.
      - From William Foster to Charlotte Foster, June 26, 1828; C406
        Concern about Charlotte's health during heat wave, Eliza is ill, urging her to leave on schedule.
      - From Charlotte Foster to Ann Eliza Foster, June 21, 1828; C407
        Pittsburgh to Cincinnati; list of strangers visiting town; social goings on; "there is a new German teacher of music come to town" (Kleber?).
      - From Ann Eliza to Charlotte, July 15, 1828; C407a
        From Louisville; tells of who she has met, goings on since her arrival; taking precautions with her health but there is no reason to worry about her.
      - From Eliza Lea to Charlotte Foster, undated; C408